.. _diabetes_dataset:

Diabetes dataset
----------------

Ten baseline variables, age, sex, body mass index, average blood
pressure, and six blood serum measurements were obtained for each of n =
442 diabetes patients, as well as the response of interest, a
quantitative measure of disease progression one year after baseline.

**Data Set Characteristics:**

:Number of Instances: 442

:Number of Attributes: First 10 columns are numeric predictive values

:Target: Column 11 is a quantitative measure of disease progression one year after baseline

:Attribute Information:
    - age     age in years
    - sex
    - bmi     body mass index
    - bp      average blood pressure
    - s1      tc, total serum cholesterol
    - s2      ldl, low-density lipoproteins
    - s3      hdl, high-density lipoproteins
    - s4      tch, total cholesterol / HDL
    - s5      ltg, possibly log of serum triglycerides level
    - s6      glu, blood sugar level

Note: Each of these 10 feature variables have been mean centered and scaled by the standard deviation times the square root of `n_samples` (i.e. the sum of squares of each column totals 1).

Source URL:
https://www4.stat.ncsu.edu/~boos/var.select/diabetes.html

For more information see:
Bradley Efron, Trevor Hastie, Iain Johnstone and Robert Tibshirani (2004) "Least Angle Regression," Annals of Statistics (with discussion), 407-499.
(https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/Papers/LARS/LeastAngle_2002.pdf)

